Our game is taking shape.
我们的游戏逐渐成形了
The game play is pretty much finished.
这个游戏快做完了
Now it's time to polish our game
我们要将它完善一下
and get it ready to build.
然后要生成应用了
Next we're going to be adding audio,
下一步是增加音频
sound effects and music.
音效和音乐
There are 3 main audio components in Unity.
Unity中的音频组件主要有3种
There are audio clips, audio sources
分别是音频剪辑,音频源
and the audio listener.
和音频监听器
We will concentrate on audio clips
我们这里只关注音频剪辑和
and audio sources.
音频源
For more details on these 3 audio components
更多关于这3中音频组件的信息
please see the information linked below.
请参考下方连接
Audio clips hold our audio data
音频剪辑保存了音频的数据
or sound files.
或者声音文件
Audio sources play our audio clips in the scene.
音频源在场景中播放音频剪辑
Let's find our audio clips.
让我们找一下我们的音频剪辑
In Assets we have an Audio folder.
在Assets目录下找到Audio文件夹
Here we can see a selection of sound
这里我们可以看到一些已经选好的
effects and a music track.
音效和音轨
If we select any 1 of the audio clips
如果我们选取任何一个音频剪辑
we will see that clip's import settings
我们可以在右侧的查看器中
in the Inspector.
看到这个音频剪辑的导入设置
The Preview window will display additional
预览窗口会展示
information about that clip.
其他关于当前剪辑的信息
If the Preview window has been closed
如果预览窗口关闭了
we can drag the Preview window's header
我们可以拖拽预览窗口的标题栏
bar up to reopen it.
将其重新打开
In the Preview window we can see
在预览窗口中
the audio clip's waveform,
我们可以看到音频剪辑的波形
we can play,
可以播放它
or loop the audio clip's audio file,
或者循环播放这个音频剪辑
and we get additional information about
我们在预览窗口的底部看到
that audio clip printed at the bottom.
当前音频剪辑的其他信息
We won't cover the details of the audio importer.
我们不会详细介绍整个音频导入器
For more information on the audio importer
更多详细信息
please see the links below.
请参考下方连接
We do want to note one important import
我们这里有一点需要注意
setting here however, and that is 3D Sound.
就是3D声音(Unity5的音频设置选项好像本身就没这个3D Sound)
For our game we want to make sure
对我们的游戏而言
all of our audio clips have 3D sound deselected.
我们需要确保所有的音频剪辑的3D sound没被勾选
This should already be set properly on the
这个项目的资源中的
assets provided with this project.
这个设定应该已经被设置好了
When an audio clip is imported as a 3D sound
当一个音频作为3D sound被导入后
Unity will compare the location
Unity会比较它的位置
of the audio source playing the audio clip
音频源播放音频剪辑
and compare it with the scene's
场景中的一个激活了的音频接收器就会
1 active audio listener
与这个音频源对比
and use the relative positions
使用相关的位置信息
to affect the clip's volume and panning.
来决定音频剪辑的声调和平移
We don't want any of this working in our
我们在目前这个简单的街机游戏中
simple arcade-style game.
并不需要这个功能
So we want to make sure 3D Sound
所以我们的3D Sound选项
has been deselected.
应该不要勾选
The audio files that we have in this project
这个项目的音频文件有
are 3 styles of explosions,
3种爆炸声
Asteroid, Enemy and Player.
小行星,敌人和玩家
A backgound music track.
一个背景音乐音轨
And 2 weapons effects.
两种武器音效
In this portion of the Space Shooter project
我们只是太空射击这个项目的一部分
we will be ignoring the Enemy sounds,
我们忽略敌人的声音
they are for later optional assignments.
这些是以后可选任务中才会用到的
We need to associate an audio clip with
我们需要把我们的音频剪辑
our explosion prefabs and our player ship.
连接到我们的爆炸预制件或者我们的玩家飞船上
The explosions need to play their audio clip
当爆炸初始化的时候
when they are first instantiated in to the scene.
爆炸的音频剪辑就要播放了
The player ship on the other hand needs
玩家飞船在
to play it's audio clip when the player
发射子弹的时候
fires their weapons.
也需要播放音频剪辑
We associate an audio clip with a
我们可以把音频剪辑和
game object by using an audio source component.
游戏对象使用音频源组件连接
The audio source plays an audio clip.
音频源负责播放音频剪辑
We can add an audio source component
我们可以先给游戏对象添加
to our game objects and then reference an audio
一个音频源的组件
clip for that source to play.
然后将音频剪辑被这个音频源引用播放
But there is an easier way to do this.
但是有一种更简单的处理方法
If we drag an audio clip on to
把音频剪辑直接
a game object Unity will create
拖拽到对应对象上
a new audio source on the game object
Unity 会自动在那个对象上新建一个音频源组件
and automatically reference the dragged audio clip.
然后自动引用拖拽过来的音频剪辑
Let's see this in action.
让我们来实践一下
We can drag assets easily from our
我们可以很容易的把资源
Project view on to game objects in our Hierarchy.
从项目视图拖拽到游戏对象的层级视图
To drag an asset like our audio clip
但是如果把一个音频剪辑资源拖拽到
on to a prefab asset
预制件的资源当中并不能这样操作
which both are in our project
因为他们都在我们的项目视图中
we can either open 2 Project view windows
我们可以通过打开2个项目视图窗口来完成操作
or we can change our existing Project view
或者我们改一下我们现有的层级视图
from using the 2 column layout
将使用两列的布局(2 column layout)
to using a single column layout.
换为使用一列的布局(a single column layout)
This will allow us to drag objects
这样我们就可以
from one part of our Project view to another
从项目视图中把资源来回拖拽
without losing focus on our target asset.
同时也不会弄丢目标
Our first target asset will be the
我们第一个要连接的目标是
asteroid explosion prefab.
小行星爆炸的预制件
Our asteroid hazards have a reference
我们的小行星引用了
to this prefab.
这个预制件
When we destroy the asteroid
当小行星被击毁的时候
the asteroid will spawn this prefab.
小行星会生成这个预制件
At that point we want it to go bang.
这时候我们希望有爆炸声
With the explosion_steroid prefab selected
explosion_steroid预制件已经被选定的情况下
drag the explosion_asteroid audio clip
将explosion_asteroid的音频剪辑
on to the game object on the Inspector and drop it.
拖拽到对象的查看窗口并松开鼠标
We can see that Unity has added an
我们看到Unity已经自动
audio source to the prefab asset
在当前预制件上添加了音频源
and that audio source has a reference
这个音频源
to the audio clip that we dragged and dropped on it.
也已经引用了我们刚才拖拽过来的音频剪辑
The bulk of the component is dedicated
这个组件的大部分内容是
to 3D Sound settings,
关于3D音效的设定
which we can safely ignore.
我们可以忽略这部分
The only important setting that we need to
唯一需要我们注意的
worry about for our game here
关于我们游戏的重要设定是
is Play On Awake.
Play On Awake
Play On Awake should be on by default.
Play On Awake默认应该被勾选了
For our explosions to work properly in our game
为了使我们的爆炸可以在游戏中正常的执行
we need to make sure that it is set on.
我们需要确保这个选项被勾选
This way the audio will play automatically
这样在产生这个爆炸的时候
when we spawn our explosion.
这个音频就会被自动播放
We can also drag an audio clip on to a
我们也可以把一个音频剪辑
prefab asset without having it
不通过查看器窗口
visable in the Inspector.
拖拽到预制件资源上
Select the explosion_player audio clip
选定explosion_player剪辑
and drag it on to the explosion_player prefab asset.
把它拖拽到explosion_player预制件上
As we are using the defaults as they are
因为默认就是Play On Awake
with Play On Awake automatically set
已经被自动选定了
we don't need to make any changes to this at all.
所以我们不需要做任何更改
Now the player's weapon sound is almost as simple.
玩家武器的声音更简单
Select the weapon_player audio clip
选定weapon_player的音频剪辑
and drag it in to the Scene view
拖拽到场景视图中
and drop it on to the player game object.
的玩家对象上
Again we can see that Unity has added
我们可以看到Unity
an audio source to the player game object
又一次帮我们把音频源
and the audio clip reference is set to
添加到了玩家对象上并对weapon_player
weapon_player.
做了引用
The player however has just a few more
这里玩家有几点需要
items to consider.
特别注意
First we definately do not want Play On Awake set.
第一,Play On Awake这个选项不要勾选
Otherwise we would get our weapon sound playing
否则我们在游戏一开始的时候
on the very first frame of the game.
就会听到物体的声音
Deselect Play On Awake.
去掉Play On Awake的勾选
Now if we won't be playing this sound automatically
如果我们不让声音自动产生
how will we play it?
那应该让声音何时播放?
We must do this from our PlayerController script.
我们需要在PlayerController脚本中处理
So select the player controller script
选定player controller脚本
and open it for editing.
打开编辑
Looking at our PlayerController script
浏览一下我们的PlayerController脚本
where do we want to write our code?
我们的代码该加在哪里呢?
In our Update function where we fire our shot.
写在Update函数中这里我们发射子弹
As all of the logic will be
所有的逻辑将会被
executed within the same frame
在同一帧中执行
practically it doesn't make a difference
因此在这段代码的
where in the block we write our new line
什么位置新增代码
as long as it is inside the if statement.
并没有什么区别,只要在这段
controlling when we fire our weapons.
控制武器发射的if条件内的添加新代码
We will add this line of code to the
我们会在这段代码
end of this block.
的结尾处添加代码
Write audio.Play with a capital P
敲入audio.Play注意P大写
followed by parenthesis.
后面跟着括弧
Audio is the shorthand reference
Audio是一个引用的缩写
that this script will use to talk
注明了这个脚本
to the audio source attached to it.
将会使用已经引用了的音频源
And Play is a function on the audio source
Play函数说明
that will play the current clip
播放当前的音频剪辑
and as a function needs to be called
作为一个函数
with the parenthesis.
它在被调用的过程中应该带括号
It is worth noting that we can change the
实际上我们可以更换要播放的
clips to be played and other
音频剪辑
additional functionality all in code
以及代码中其他附加的函数
but we won't be covering that here.
但是这里并不会做详细介绍
For more information on the audio source
更多关于音频源
or any of the other audio components
或者其他音频组件的信息
please see the details linked below.
请参考下方连接
Now when we fire our weapon we instantiate
现在我们可以让武器开火,实例化我们的激光子弹
our shot clone and play our weapon sound.
同时发出发射子弹的声音
Save this script, return to Unity,
保存这个脚本回到Unity
save the scene and enter Play mode.
保存场景并进入游戏模式
And we have sound effects.
我们已经有音效了
Exit Play mode.
退出游戏模式
Along with our sound effects we also have a
除了音效外
background music track.
我们还有一个背景音轨
we can find this in our audio folder
我们可以在audio文件夹中找到
as music_background.
music_background文件
Let's put this background music
让我们把背景音乐加入我们的
on our game controller.
游戏控制器中
This audio track will be self sufficient
这个音轨是自己独立运行的
and won't need to interact with a
不会受到游戏控制的
game controller at all.
任何影响
It could go on it's own game object.
它可以自己独立作为一个对象
But the game controller's game object
但是如果把背景音乐音轨
is a tidy place to keep a component
加入到game controller中就会
that is related to the game in general.
让整体感觉很简洁并且相关性更好
Drag music_background in to our
把music_background拖拽到
Scene view and drop it on Game Controller.
我们场景视图的Game Controller对象上
This will add a new audio source
这会在Game Controller增加
to Game Controller with music_background
一个新的关联了music_background剪辑的
as the referenced clip.
音频源
We want this music to start right away
我们希望背景音乐在游戏启动时马上开始
and play during the entire game.
并且在游戏中不停的播放
For this we want to make sure that
因此我们需要确认
Play On Awake is selected
Play On Awake(游戏开始时播放)已勾选
so it will begin playing on the first frame
背景音轨在游戏一开始就会播放
and select Loop as well.
同时选定循环播放
So the audio runs continuously.x
因此音频就会不停播放
The audio clip is designed as a seamless loop
这个音频剪辑已经被设计成一个无缝的循环
so there will be no audible gap when the
所以在音乐循环往复的过程中听不到
music continuously restarts.
音频上的间隔
Save the scene and enter Play mode.
保存场景进入游戏模式
Now we have sound effects and music.
现在我们已经有了音效和音乐
Exit Play mode.
退出游戏模式
The last step we need to take is
最后一步就是调整不同音频
balancing the audio.
的大小
All of the clips are currently being played back
所有的剪辑目前都是最大的声音播放
at full volume, and they don't mix well.
他们混合的并不理想
Let's bring some of these effects down in volume.
让我们把一些音效的声音调小一点
Select the player game object and
选定玩家对象
bring up the audio source component.
找到音频源这个组件
Change the Volume property to 0.5.
将音量属性设置为0.5
This will reduce the strength of the
这样会减小玩家
player's weapon sound.
武器发射的声音
Next select the Game Controller game object
下一步选定Game Controller这个对象
and again on the audio component
再次找到音频组件
reduce the volume property to 0.5.
把音量调正为0.5
Save the scene and enter Play mode.
保存场景进入游戏模式
Now the explosions are still bright and snappy
现在爆炸的声音依然响亮
but the player's weapons and the background
玩家武器和背景音乐
music are not so overwhelming.
的声音也不那么吵闹了
Excellent.
很棒
In the next assignment we will see how to
下一项任务是
display a score.
如何显示得分